QUESTIONS = [
  {
    "question": "This method of _______________ consists in the constructive dialectical process of opposition and reconciliation.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Hegel",
      "B": "Socrates",
      "C": "Plato",
      "D": "Descartes"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A critical and philosophical look at law in its generality is the function of a discipline called _________________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Jurisprudence",
      "B": "Normative law",
      "C": "Ethical Law",
      "D": "Metaphysics"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The conception of Philosophy that is used to characterize a person or a group of persons' attitude to life",
    "options": {
      "A": "Under-labourer Conception",
      "B": "Philosophy as Wisdom",
      "C": "Master Scientist conception of Philosophy",
      "D": "Philosophy as search for truth"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ is a branch of Philosophy that is defined as the science of being as being.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Ethics",
      "B": "Axiology",
      "C": "Metaphysics",
      "D": "Epistemology"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Etymologically Philosophy is derived from the Greek word",
    "options": {
      "A": "Logos",
      "B": "Wisdom",
      "C": "Reason",
      "D": "Philos"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the following is not a six step in every scientific inquiry.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Observation",
      "B": "Questioning",
      "C": "Generalization",
      "D": "Hypothesis"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The method of ________________ takes reason to be the sole means of acquiring philosophical knowledge.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Appraisal",
      "B": "Rationalism",
      "C": "Reductionism",
      "D": "Empiricism"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "An average scientist always seeks for explanation while the philosopher basically seeks for __________________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Love",
      "B": "Engagement",
      "C": "Justification",
      "D": "Details"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ is a school of thought in epistemology which holds that human beings can acquire knowledge of reality using our minds alone, by thinking or pure reason.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Empiricism",
      "B": "Conditionalism",
      "C": "Rationalism",
      "D": "Reductionism"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________________ is considered the first philosopher in the western world.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Socrates",
      "B": "Russell",
      "C": "Plato",
      "D": "Thales"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a _________________, the role of reason is basically one of interpreting and defending the dogma derived from sources whose authority and truth is taken on faith.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Scientist",
      "B": "Religionist",
      "C": "Sociologist",
      "D": "Philosopher"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A method of Philosophy that confined to sense experience.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Empiricism",
      "B": "Reductionism",
      "C": "Appraisal approach",
      "D": "Rationalism"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "All EXCEPT one is not a type of Ethics.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Normative",
      "B": "Reductive",
      "C": "Meta-Ethics",
      "D": "Descriptive"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of these is a major usefulness of Philosophy.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Love",
      "B": "Reflection",
      "C": "Domination",
      "D": "Scientism"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Skepticism is also known as _____________________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Hedonism",
      "B": "Pyrrhonism",
      "C": "Cynicism",
      "D": "Stoicism"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philosophy grew out of wonder and _____________________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Desire",
      "B": "Curiosity",
      "C": "Prayer",
      "D": "Enlightenment"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____________________ as source of knowledge occurs when we make certain claims to knowledge based on the authority of someone who is a specialist in the particular field of knowledge.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Authority",
      "B": "Sense Experience",
      "C": "Revelation",
      "D": "Reason"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "All EXCEPT one is not a branch of Philosophy.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Metaphysics",
      "B": "Psychology",
      "C": "Ethics",
      "D": "Epistemology"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the following is not a method of Philosophy.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Pragmatic method",
      "B": "Socratic Method",
      "C": "Dialectics Method of Plato",
      "D": "Scientific Method"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "\u201c\u201dNothing is static and everything in the state of flux\u201d\u201d is attributed to which philosopher.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Anaximenex",
      "B": "Anaximander",
      "C": "Thales",
      "D": "Heraclitus"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Medieval Christian philosophers were all part of a movement called ________________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Scholasticism",
      "B": "Philosophers",
      "C": "Socratic Movement",
      "D": "Analytic Philosophers"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "________________ is a modern Philosopher who described in his famous book \"Leviathan\" how the natural state of mankind was brute-like and poor, and how the modern state was a kind of \"social contract\".",
    "options": {
      "A": "Russell",
      "B": "Carnap",
      "C": "John Austin",
      "D": "Hobbes"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________________ is best known as the originator of the Ontological Argument for the existence of God by abstract reasoning alone.",
    "options": {
      "A": "St Thomas Aquinas",
      "B": "St Jude",
      "C": "St Augustine",
      "D": "St Anselm"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ is the only discipline that strictly lays down the rules which the mind must follow to arrive at truth and thereby minimize if not totally eradicate error.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Epistemology",
      "B": "Reasoning",
      "C": "Philosophy",
      "D": "Logic"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A group that believes that there is no absolute truth and two points of view can be acceptable at the same time.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Cynicism",
      "B": "Hedonism",
      "C": "Sophism",
      "D": "Stoicism"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The act by which the mind affirms or denies something of something else is called what?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Reasoning",
      "B": "Simple Apprehension",
      "C": "Relevance of Logic",
      "D": "Judgement in Logic"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "All EXCEPT one is not one of the etymological meaning of Logic.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Argumentative",
      "B": "Reason",
      "C": "Reductionsim",
      "D": "Dialectical"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "______________ is a theory and method of interpretation.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Dialectics",
      "B": "Phenomenology",
      "C": "Analytic",
      "D": "Hermeneutics"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The age regarded as the period of revival of classical civilization and learning, which occurred in the 15th and 16th Century.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Modern",
      "B": "Contemporary",
      "C": "Renaissance",
      "D": "Classical"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "20th Century philosophy was dominated to a great extent by the rivalry between these two philosophical traditions, Analytic Philosophy and ________________ Philosophy",
    "options": {
      "A": "Inductive",
      "B": "Systematic",
      "C": "Continental",
      "D": "Deductive"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Roughly Speaking, 17th\u00a0and 18th\u00a0Century were regarded as the age of Reason and _____________________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Development",
      "B": "Philosophy",
      "C": "Enlightenment",
      "D": "Computation"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "______________ believed that Empiricism and rationalism could be combined.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Kant",
      "B": "Hobbes",
      "C": "Hegel",
      "D": "Voltaire"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The age regarded as the period of revival of classical civilization and learning, which occurred in the 15th and 16th Century.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Classical",
      "B": "Contemporary",
      "C": "Modern",
      "D": "Renaissance"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the following is not a current in African Philosophy.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Inductive Philosophy",
      "B": "Sage Philosophy",
      "C": "Ethno Philosophy",
      "D": "Professional Philosophy"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________________ founded the Positivism Movement in the Contemporary Period.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Descartes",
      "B": "Kant",
      "C": "Hobbes",
      "D": "Comte"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A group that believes that there is no absolute truth and two points of view can be acceptable at the same time.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Cynicism",
      "B": "Hedonism",
      "C": "Stoicism",
      "D": "Sophism"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________________ is best known as the originator of the Ontological Argument for the existence of God by abstract reasoning alone.",
    "options": {
      "A": "St Thomas Aquinas",
      "B": "St Jude",
      "C": "St Augustine",
      "D": "St Anselm"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "________________ is a modern Philosopher who described in his famous book \"Leviathan\" how the natural state of mankind was brute-like and poor, and how the modern state was a kind of \"social contract\".",
    "options": {
      "A": "Russell",
      "B": "Hobbes",
      "C": "Carnap",
      "D": "John Austin"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a group of propositions that can be structured into two parts that ispremise(s)\u2019, which is also known as \u2018reason\u2019 and \u2018conclusion\u2019 which can also be known as \u2018claim\u2019.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Premise",
      "B": "An Argument",
      "C": "Conclusion",
      "D": "Square of Opposition"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ is an Opposite of Deductive Logic",
    "options": {
      "A": "Inductive Logic",
      "B": "Propositional Logic",
      "C": "Mathematical Logic",
      "D": "Boolean Logic"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "This form of logic is concerned with testing the truth-value validity of propositions through logical rules and principles is called __________________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Boolean Logic",
      "B": "Propositional Logic",
      "C": "Mathematical Logic",
      "D": "Formal Logic"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A definition that tries to identify the intention of a term by providing a synonymous linguistic expression or an operational procedure for determining the applicability of the term is known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "Lexical Definition",
      "B": "Denotative Definition",
      "C": "Intentional Definition",
      "D": "Connotative Definition"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "That kind of argument that its premise(s) only support, but do not guarantee its conclusion is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "Boolean Argument",
      "B": "Deductive Argument",
      "C": "Inductive argument",
      "D": "Mathematical Argument"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A definition where a term whether new or existing is given a new meaning for the purpose of argument or discussion in a given context.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Stipulative Definition",
      "B": "Recursive Definition",
      "C": "Definition by Genus and Difference",
      "D": "Lexical Definition"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "In logic, an _______________ is the process by which one proposition is arrived at and affirmed based on one or more other propositions accepted as the starting point of the process",
    "options": {
      "A": "Inference",
      "B": "Premiss",
      "C": "Premise Indicator",
      "D": "Conclusion"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the following is not a type of categorical proposition.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Universal Affirmative proposition",
      "B": "Particular Affirmative Proposition",
      "C": "Particular Conclusive proposition",
      "D": "Universal Negative proposition"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ fallacy occurs when such a word is used in a manner that implies different meanings or senses of the word within the same context.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Modus Tollen",
      "B": "Equivocation",
      "C": "Modus Ponens",
      "D": "Ad Hominem"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_________________ is a definition identical with dictionary Definition.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Intentional Definition",
      "B": "Theoretical Definition",
      "C": "Lexical Definition",
      "D": "Denotative Defintion"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A critical thinking by Africans on their experiences of reality can be defined as _____________",
    "options": {
      "A": "Pure Philosophy",
      "B": "Black Philosophy",
      "C": "African Philosophy",
      "D": "Afri-European Philosophy"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The age or period where most of the philosophers were mainly concerned with proving the existence of God.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Modern Period",
      "B": "Ancient Period",
      "C": "Contemporary Period",
      "D": "Medieval Period"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____________ is a Christian Humanist whose book \"Utopia\" influenced generations of politicians and planners.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Thomas Moore",
      "B": "Russell",
      "C": "Bacon",
      "D": "Erasmus"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ was the founder of Phenomenology a great and very influential movement of the 20th\u00a0Century.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Kant",
      "B": "Hegel",
      "C": "Edmund Husserl",
      "D": "Hobbes"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Apart from John Locke, one of these Islamic Philosophers introduced the idea of \u201c\u201dTabula Rasa\u201d\u201d",
    "options": {
      "A": "Augustine",
      "B": "Maimonides",
      "C": "Averroes",
      "D": "Avicenna"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "An argument is said to be ______________-when the conclusion of that argument is derived from or follows from the premises.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Invalid",
      "B": "Sound",
      "C": "Valid",
      "D": "Conclusive"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "____________ refers to that proposition or statement, within an argument, which provides support for or grounds for asserting the conclusion of that argument.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Premise Indicator",
      "B": "Inference",
      "C": "Premise",
      "D": "Conclusion"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "All EXCEPT one is a function of Language.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Conclusive Function",
      "B": "Expressive Function",
      "C": "Notation Function",
      "D": "Divine Function"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____________ fallacy occurs whenever a conclusion is defended by a threat to the well- being of those who do not accept it.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Ad Hominem",
      "B": "Ad Populum",
      "C": "Ad Baculum",
      "D": "Ad Datum"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "All Black women are beautiful           Cacy Ngamen is a black woma               Therefore, Cacy Ngamen is beautiful",
    "options": {
      "A": "A Reduction",
      "B": "A Conclusion",
      "C": "A Proposition",
      "D": "A syllogism"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "A valid deductive argument is said to be _______________ if the premises of that argument as well as the conclusion are all true prepositions.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Invalid",
      "B": "Sound",
      "C": "Conclusive",
      "D": "Valid"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Roughly Speaking, 17th\u00a0and 18th\u00a0Century were regarded as the age of Reason and",
    "options": {
      "A": "Enlightenment",
      "B": "Development",
      "C": "Philosophy",
      "D": "Computation"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "p \u1d10 q      p     Therefore q      The above is what Argument form.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Simplification",
      "B": "Modus Tollen",
      "C": "Modus ponens",
      "D": "Addition"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the one that does not belong to this group.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Consequently",
      "B": "It follows",
      "C": "Therefore",
      "D": "While"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The formal fallacy associated with the deviation from the Modus Ponens rule is called",
    "options": {
      "A": "Fallacy of affirming the consequent",
      "B": "Fallacy affirming the antecedent",
      "C": "Fallacy affirming an invalid argument",
      "D": "Fallacy affirming the conclusion"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The formal fallacy that is associated with the deviation from the Modus Tollens\u2019 rule which is also known as",
    "options": {
      "A": "Fallacy denying the argument",
      "B": "Fallacy denying the consequent",
      "C": "Fallacy of denying the antecedent.",
      "D": "Fallacy denying the conclusion"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______________ was the founder of Phenomenology a great and very influential movement of the 20th\u00a0Century.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Hegel",
      "B": "Edmund Husserl",
      "C": "Kant",
      "D": "Hobbes"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Traditionally, logic is divided into two main branches namely formal and ______",
    "options": {
      "A": "Inductive Logic",
      "B": "Informal Logic",
      "C": "Deductive Logic",
      "D": "Mathematical Logic"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philosophy is the only discipline that is ___ in nature",
    "options": {
      "A": "old",
      "B": "universal ",
      "C": "scientific",
      "D": "athestic"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "__ is regarded as a group of propositions whose function is to make a claim about something",
    "options": {
      "A": "dissertation ",
      "B": "law ",
      "C": "argument",
      "D": " philosophy"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Observation and understanding supernatural phenomenon and control processes is the main task of _______",
    "answer": "science",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The method of _____ takes reason to be the sole means of acquiring philosophical knowledge.",
    "answer": "rationalism",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Logos, the Greek word from which Logic derived does not mean __",
    "options": {
      "A": "discorse",
      "B": "study",
      "C": "word",
      "D": "life"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Greek word for wisdom is ___",
    "options": {
      "A": "sophia ",
      "B": "philosophy ",
      "C": "philo",
      "D": " alethia"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The natural sciences broke away from philosophy in ___",
    "options": {
      "A": "18th century ",
      "B": "19th century ",
      "C": "17th century ",
      "D": "20th century"
    },
    "answer": "A",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The philosophical idea that establishes the world as a product of a single understanding substance is known is called ______",
    "answer": "Monism",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The method of rationalism takes reason to be the sole means of acquiring philosophical knowledge. True or False ________",
    "answer": "True",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Apart from John Locke, one of these Islamic Philosophers introduced the idea of \u201c\u201dTabula Rasa\u201d\u201d",
    "options": {
      "A": "Averroes",
      "B": "Avicenna",
      "C": "Augustine",
      "D": "Maimonides"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The critical or transcendental method of philosophy ______takes stock of the arguments of empiricism and rationalism and builds a new system of tremendous importance in the history of philosophic thought.",
    "answer": "Kant",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____ method of philosophy consists in the constructive dialectical process of opposition and reconciliation",
    "answer": "Hegel",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Identifying a complex argument involves a complex reasoning. True or False ____",
    "answer": "True",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The words Definiendum and definiens are two key words you must master before you can understand the method of definition by",
    "answer": "Genus and Difference.",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Recursive definition is sometimes referred to as",
    "answer": "Inductive",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Argumentum ad Baculum means _____",
    "answer": "Appeal to force",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The words Definiendum and definiens are two key words you must master before you can understand the method of definition by",
    "answer": "Genus and Difference.",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Recursive definition is sometimes referred to as",
    "answer": "Inductive",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Argumentum ad Baculum means _____",
    "answer": "Appeal to force",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "____ fallacy mostly occurs when we misinterpret someone's original statement or intention",
    "answer": "Amphiboly",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The idea that only change is constant is from ______",
    "answer": "Heraclitus",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "To the ______ we can never know the true inner substance of things, only how they appear to us",
    "answer": "sceptics",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nationalist and ideological philosophy is also known as a sub of______ in African philosophy.",
    "answer": "Professional philosophy",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "___ regrded fire as the primary substance of all reality",
    "answer": "Heraclitus",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "Thales identified ___ as the primary substance of the universe",
    "options": {
      "A": "ashes",
      "B": "cold",
      "C": "water ",
      "D": "sand"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "___ is not among the sources of philosophy",
    "options": {
      "A": "curiousity ",
      "B": "sense of wonder ",
      "C": "desire for knowledge for its sake",
      "D": " idleness and poverty"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first standard comment about the nature and definition of philosophy was made by ___",
    "answer": "Pythagoras",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "___ had his philosophical training in Africa",
    "options": {
      "A": "Plato ",
      "B": "Pythagoras",
      "C": " Augustine ",
      "D": "Confucius"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Western Philosophy originated in___",
    "answer": "Miletus",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Honesty is my best policy\" is an expression of ____",
    "options": {
      "A": "One's religious belief ",
      "B": "One's philosophy of life ",
      "C": "Declaration of one's honesty",
      "D": " Manifestation of one's righteousness"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "Every philosopher define philosophy in his or her own way because philosophy is ___",
    "answer": "complex",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In logic, another name for statement is __",
    "options": {
      "A": "truth ",
      "B": "proposition ",
      "C": "fact of matter",
      "D": " conceptual analysis"
    },
    "answer": "B",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "___ is the logical process exhibited in this statement: All lecturers are homosexuals",
    "answer": "judgement",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "All EXCEPT one is not a type of Ethics.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Meta-Ethics",
      "B": "Descriptive",
      "C": "Reductive",
      "D": "Normative"
    },
    "answer": "C",
    "type": "mcq"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first standard comment about the nature and definition of philosophy was made by ___",
    "answer": "Pythagoras",
    "type": "fill"
  },
  {
    "question": "____________ was the founder of Phenomenology a great and very influential movement of the 20th\u00a0Century.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Hegel",
      "B": "Kant",
      "C": "Hobbes",
      "D": "Edmund Husserl"
    },
    "answer": "D",
    "type": "mcq"
  }
]